Guide to the Graduate School Records, 1924-2014 UA.24.01.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession UA85-67, 1964-1970
  - Graduate School Committee on the Administration of the Foreign Language Examinations, 1964-1970 (Box 84)
- Accession UA85-107, 1984-1985
  - Graduate School, Dean of Records, 1984-1985 (Box 85)
- Accession UA89-65, 1950-1986 and undated
  - Academic Administration, Duke University, Prior to, 1982 (Box 86)
  - Trustees, Board of, Academic Affairs Committee, Education Report (Box 86)
  - Academic Council, 1985-1986 (Box 86)
  - Academic Council, 1983-1984 (Box 86)
  - Academic Council, 1982-1983 (Box 86)
  - Academic Council, 1981-1982 (Box 86)
  - Academic Management Information System (Box 86)
  - Outlook for Academic Positions, Comparative Report, 1980 (Box 86)
  - Ad Hoc Science Committee, Washington DC, 1980-1981 (Box 86)
  - Admissions and Financial Aid, Advisory Committee on (Box 86)
  - African American Institute Correspondence (Box 86)
  - African American Institute, General Information (Box 86)
  - American Association of University Professors, Duke University Chapter (Box 86)
  - American Council on Education (ACE), Rating of Graduate Programs (Box 86)
  - Arts and Sciences Development Campaign (Box 86)
  - Asian/Pacific Studies Institute (Box 86)
  - Biotechnology, 1983-1984 (Box 87)
  - Blue Sky, Summer, 1984 (Box 87)
  - Canadian Studies, 1983-1985 (Box 87)
  - Canadian Studies, 1981-1983 (Box 87)
  - Canadian Studies, 1980-1981 (Box 87)
  - Canadian Studies Center Grant Proposal, 1981 (Box 87)
  - International Studies, Center for, 1985-1986 (Box 87)
  - International Studies, Center for, 1982-1983 (Box 87)
  - International Studies, Center for, 1983-1984 (Box 87)
  - International Studies, Center for, 1984-1985 (Box 87)
  - International Studies, University Self-Study for Southern Association of Colleges (SAC) Reaccreditation (Box 87)
  - International House (Box 87)
  - International Studies, Center for, 1981-1982 (Box 87)
  - International Studies, Center for, 1979-1981 (Box 87)
  - International Studies, Center for, Director Search (Box 87)
  - International Studies, Director Search (Box 87)
  - Degrees Granted, Graduate (Box 87)
  - Ph.D. Recipients, Destinations of, 1984-1985 (Box 87)
  - Degree Recipients, Graduate, Destinations of, 1983 (Box 87)
  - Degree Recipients, Graduate, Destinations of, 1981-1982 (Box 87)
  - Degree Recipients, Graduate, Destinations of, 1978-1980 (Box 88)
  - Degree Recipients, Graduate, Destinations of, 1959-1961, 1975-1977 (Box 88)
  - Endowment, Duke, 1982-1984 (Box 88)
  - Endowment, Duke (Box 88)
  - Endowment, Duke, Special Colloquia, 1984 (Box 88)
  - Endowment, Duke, 1980-1982 (Box 88)
  - Endowment, Duke (Box 88)
  - Development, Office of; See also Alumni (Box 88)
  - Education Department, School Administration Ed.D. Program Proposal (Box 88)
  - Education Department, 1981-1982 (Box 88)
  - Education Department, 1977-1979 (Box 88)
  - Education Department, 1980-1981 (Box 88)
  - Education Department (Box 89)
  - Education Department, 1973-1976 (Box 89)
  - Education Department, 1971-1972 (Box 89)
  - Education Department, University Self-Study for Southern Association of Colleges (SAC) Reaccreditation, 1976 (Box 89)
  - Education Department, 1950-1970 (Box 89)
  - Education Department, Master of Arts in Teaching (MAT) Cooperative Program, 1953-1965 (Box 89)
  - Education Department, Off-Campus Programs (Box 89)
  - Education Department, Sahem Fund, Program Proposal for Improvement of Writing (Box 89)
  - Genetics, Training Program; See also Bio Science Council (Box 89)
  - Genetics Program (Box 89)
  - Compliance Review, U. S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare (HEW), 1979-1980 (Box 89)
  - Organization for Tropical Studies (OTS), 1979-1982 (Box 89)
  - Institute of the Arts, Search, 1984-1985 (Box 89)
  - IBM (Box 89)
  - National Humanities Center, Research Triangle Park (RTP) (Box 90)
  - Graduate Student Admissions, Iraqi (Box 90)
  - International Populations Institute (Box 90)
  - International Studies, Committee on (Box 90)
  - Commonwealth Studies, Institute on, University of London (Box 90)
  - Humanities, Future of the Humanities at Duke Ad Hoc Committee, 1980-1981 (Box 90)
  - Graduate and Professional Student Council (Box 90)
  - Faculty Meetings, Graduate, 1969-1974 (Box 90)
  - Institutional Advancement, Office of (Box 90)
  - Humanities Council, Duke University (Box 90)
  - University Review Committee on the Use of Human Subjects in Non-Medical Research, 1978-1979 (Box 90)
  - Hazardous Waste Management Research Center, Gerald Stairs (Box 90)
  - Duke Press, 1985-1986 (Box 90)
  - President, Report to, 1977 (Box 90)
  - Policy Sciences and Public Affairs, Duke Institute for, Joel L. Fleishman (Box 90)
  - Policy Sciences (Box 90)
  - Phytotron (Box 90)
  - Pfizer (Box 90)
  - Pew, R. Anderson, Pew Memorial Trust (Box 90)
  - Oak Ridge Associated Universities (Box 90)
  - Biotechnology Center, North Carolina (Box 90)
  - Biotechnology Center, North Carolina, Committee (Box 90)
  - Nixon, Richard M., Presidential Library (Box 90)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF), Organized Research Units Project, 1980 (Box 90)
  - Primate Facility (Box 90)
  - Shell International Studies Research Fellowships (Box 90)
  - Lindsey, Dr. Quentin W., Advisor to Governor, North Carolina (Box 90)
  - Library, Perkins, University Self-Study for Southern Association of Colleges (SAC) Reaccreditation, 1976 (Box 90)
  - Library External Review (Box 90)
  - Kellogg National Fellowship Program (Box 90)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) (Box 90)
  - National Research Council, Committee on Assessment of Quality-Related Characteristics of Research-Doctorate Programs in the US (Box 91)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH), Challenge Grant, 1980 (Box 91)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) (Box 91)
  - National Center for Resource Recovery, Inc. (Box 91)
  - Linguistic Atlas of Mid and South Atlantic States (Box 91)
  - University Self-Study for Southern Association of Colleges (SAC) Reaccreditation, 1976 (Box 91)
  - Triangle Universities Computation Center (TUCC) (Box 91)
  - Triangle Universities Nuclear Laboratories (TUNL) (Box 91)
  - Tuition Rates, Special (Box 91)
  - Universities Research Association, Inc. (Fermilab) (Box 91)
  - Wooten, Carl B., Office of Patent Administration (Box 91)
  - Women's Studies, Duke/UNC Center for (Box 91)
  - Triangle Universities Center for Advanced Studies, Inc. (TUCASI) (Box 91)
  - Triangle Universities Center for Advanced Studies, Inc. (TUCASI), 1985-1986 (Box 91)
  - U. S. Army Russian Institute (USARI) (Box 91)
  - Student Perspective, 1970 (Box 91)
  - Teacher Education at Duke University (Box 91)
  - Recommendations, Actions, Letters and Memoranda Re: the Location of the Arts Center and the Development of the Woman's College Campus, Chronological Record of, 1963 Nov. 9 (Box 91)
- Accession UA2002-64, 2001-2002
  - Master of Arts in Teaching Program, Planning Committee, Celebrating 150 years, Education Leadership Speeches, 2002 (Box 92)
  - Master of Arts in Teaching Program, Planning Committee, Celebrating 150 years, Records, 2001-2002 (Box 92)
- Accession UA2004-83, 1986-2002 and undated
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1999 Aug. 23-2000 Feb. 11 (Box 93)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1999 May 19-2000 Apr. 3 (Box 93)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1999 Apr. 19-2000 May 3 (Box 93)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1994 Sept. 20-1994 Nov. 15 (Box 93)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1994 Aug. 15-1994 Nov. 30 (Box 93)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1999 Nov. 12-2000 Apr. 20 (Box 93)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 2001 Apr. 2-2001 Apr. 27 (Box 93)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 2000 Oct. 4-2000 Oct. 6 (Box 93)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 2000 Oct. 21-2000 Dec. 12 (Box 93)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 2000 Apr. 28-2001 Feb. 8 (Box 93)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1998 Mar. 23-1998 Oct. 20 (Box 93)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1998 Oct. 16-1999 Mar. 5 (Box 93)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1999 Mar. 19-1999 Apr. 23 (Box 93)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1994 Apr. 5-1994 May 3 (Box 93)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1994 Feb. 1-1994 Feb. 24 (Box 93)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1994 Jan. 12-1994 Feb. 9 (Box 93)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1993 Nov. 2-1993 Nov. 9 (Box 93)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1996 Feb. 23-1996 Sept. 9 (Box 94)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1993 Sept.-1996 June 7 (Box 94)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1996 Oct. 29-1997 Feb. 11 (Box 94)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1995 Dec. 12-1996 June 12 (Box 94)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1996 Feb. 5 (Box 94)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1997 Apr. 15-1997 May 2 (Box 94)
  - Enrollment Reports, 1998 (Box 94)
  - Enrollment Reports, 1997 Fall (Box 94)
  - Enrollment Reports, 1996 (Box 94)
  - Enrollment Reports, 1994-1995 (Box 94)
  - Enrollment Reports, 1992-1993 (Box 94)
  - Enrollment Reports, 1986-1991 (Box 94)
  - Enrollment Reports, 1997 Spring (Box 94)
  - Enrollment Reports, 1995-1996 (Box 94)
  - Inner Staff, 2000 Dec. 19-2001 Feb. 12 (Box 94)
  - Inner Staff, 2001 Feb. 26-2001 Mar. 30 (Box 94)
  - Inner Staff, 2001 Jan. 8-2001 Mar. 14 (Box 94)
  - Inner Staff, 1999 Sept. 29-2000 Sept. 29 (Box 94)
  - Inner Staff, 2000 Sept. 22-2000 Oct. 16 (Box 94)
  - Inner Staff, 2000 Oct. 16-2001 June 18 (Box 94)
  - Arts and Sciences Department By-Laws: Public Policy-Zoology (Box 94)
  - Arts and Sciences Department By-Laws: History-Psychology (Box 94)
  - Arts and Sciences Department By-Laws: Computer Science-Health, PE and Recreation (Box 94)
  - Arts and Sciences Department By-Laws: AALL-Classical Study (Box 94)
  - Arts and Sciences Department By-Laws: AAAS (Box 95)
  - Arts and Sciences Department By-Laws, 1997-2002 (Box 95)
  - Dean's Cabinet, 2000 July 7-2000 Oct. 26 (Box 95)
  - Dean's Cabinet (Missing), 1999 July 14-2001 Feb. 14 (Box 95)
  - Dean's Cabinet, 2001 Feb. 19-2001 Mar. 16 (Box 95)
  - Dean's Cabinet, 2001 Mar. 28-2001 June 8 (Box 95)
  - Dean's Cabinet, 2002 Feb. 20-2002 Mar. 1 (Box 95)
  - Dean's Cabinet, 2002 Apr. 12-2002 May 10 (Box 95)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1993 Sept. 21-1993 Oct. 28 (Box 95)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1993 Sept. 21 (Box 95)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1993 Sept. 21 (Box 95)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1993 Aug. 26-1993 Sept. 14 (Box 95)
  - Inner Staff, 2000 June 1 (Box 95)
  - Inner Staff, 2000 June 13-2000 July 24 (Box 95)
  - Inner Staff, 2000 Jan. 4-2000 Aug. 18 (Box 95)
  - Inner Staff, 2000 Aug. 7-2000 Sept. 13 (Box 95)
  - Inner Staff, 1999 July 16-1999 Aug. 18 (Box 95)
  - Inner Staff, 1999 June 17-1999 Nov. 29 (Box 95)
  - Inner Staff, 1999 July 15-2000 May 4 (Box 95)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1996 Apr. 10-1996 Apr. 12 (Box 95)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1994 June 7-1996 Mar. 29 (Box 95)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1996 Jan. 15-1996 Mar. 1 (Box 95)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1995 Nov. 21-1996 Feb. 16 (Box 95)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1995 Oct. 24-1995 Nov. 15 (Box 96)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1994 Sept. 1 (Box 96)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1994 Sept. 1-1995 Sept. 19 (Box 96)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1997 July 14-1997 Nov. 13 (Box 96)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1997 Oct. 17-1997 Dec. 9 (Box 96)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1997 Dec. 9-1998 Apr. 8 (Box 96)
  - Inner Staff, 1999-2000 (Box 96)
  - Inner Staff, 2000 Jan. 14-2000 Mar. 6 (Box 96)
  - Inner Staff, 2000 Mar. 7-2000 Apr. 11 (Box 96)
  - Inner Staff, 2000 Mar. 25-2000 Apr. 11 (Box 96)
  - Inner Staff, 2000 May 22-2000 June 2 (Box 96)
  - Dean's Cabinet, 1999 July 20-1999 Oct. 18 (Box 96)
  - Dean's Cabinet, 1999 Aug. 6-2000-Jan. 24 (Box 96)
  - Dean's Cabinet, 2000 Feb. 16-2000 Mar. 20 (Box 96)
  - Dean's Cabinet, 2000 Apr. 7-2000 June 2 (Box 96)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1991 Mar. 7-1993 May 4 (Box 96)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 193 Jan. 5-1993 Feb. 9 (Box 96)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1993 Mar. 3 (Box 96)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1993 Mar. 30 (Box 96)
  - Inner Staff, 1999 Aug. 10-1999 Sept. 1 (Box 96)
  - Inner Staff, 1998 Dec. 18-1999 Sept. 15 (Box 96)
  - Inner Staff, 1998 Dec. 17-1999 Oct. 26 (Box 97)
  - Inner Staff, 1999 Oct. 26-2000 Jan. 14 (Box 97)
  - Inner Staff, 1999 Dec. 18-2000 Feb. 7 (Box 97)
  - Inner Staff, 1999 June 17-1999 Nov. 16 (Box 97)
  - Inner Staff, 1999 July 13-1999 Nov. 19 (Box 97)
  - Inner Staff, 1998-1999 Sept. 7 (Box 97)
  - Inner Staff, 1999 July 30-1999 Aug. 11 (Box 97)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1995 May 4-1995 Sept. 19 (Box 97)
  - Biohazard Science and Environmental Safety - MS Proposal, 1992 (Box 97)
  - Biological Structure Training Program, circa 1980-1989 (Box 97)
  - Duke Initiatives in Science Education, 1993 (Box 97)
  - Harris Fellowship Program, 1990-1991 (Box 97)
  - Health Policy Research and Education, 1986 (Box 97)
  - Health Psychology Proposal, 1988 (Box 97)
  - Master of Fine Arts Proposal, 1986 (Box 97)
  - Mellon Minority Undergraduate Fellowship, 1998 (Box 97)
  - National Consortium of Educational Access, 1989 (Box 97)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1995 Jan. 31 (Box 97)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1995 Feb. 7-1995 Feb. 21 (Box 97)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1995 Mar. 7-1995 Apr. 22 (Box 97)
  - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1994 Aug. 19-1994 Sept. 14 (Box 97)
  - Dean's Cabinet, 1999 July 14-2001 Feb. 14 (Box 97)
- Accession UA2014.0068: Education of Ida Owens documentary records, 2013-2014
  Access Restrictions
  Electronic records in this collection have been migrated to a library server and digital use copies can only be accessed onsite in the Rubenstein Library Reading Room. To request access, please contact Research Services before coming to use these records.
  Scope and Contents
  The materials in this accession are directly related to the documentary The Education of Ida Owens: Science, Civil Rights, and the Integration of Duke University, directed by Ivan Weiss. Created as the result of a collaboration between the Graduate School and Ivan Weiss during the commemoration of the 50th anniversary of desegregation at Duke University, the documentary focuses on Ida Owens, the first African American woman to receive a doctorate from Duke. The accession includes extensive interview footage and other moving image, audio, text, and photograph materials used in the creation of the documentary as well as the final version of the film. Also included is electronic documentation related to Ida Owens and the creation of the documentary, as well as print copies of promotional materials surrounding the film and the anniversary of desegregation at Duke.
  The majority of the materials in this collection are in digital format, including compressed and uncompressed moving image and audio files, still image files, and word processing files.
  - The Education of Ida Owens: Science, Civil Rights, and the Integration of Duke University: final version, 2014
  - Ida Owens background materials
  - Interview footage: Onye Akwari, first black Professor of Surgery, Duke University
  - Interview footage: Charles Anamelechi, PhD in Biomedical Engineering, Duke Univeristy '08
  - Interview footage: J. Joesph Blum, Ida Owens' advisor, James B. Duke Professor Emeritus of Cell Biology, Duke University
  - Interview footage: Samuel DuBois Cook, first black Professor, Duke University
  - Interview footage: Raymond Gavins, first black History Professor, Duke University
  - Interview footage: Craufurd Goodwin, Secretary of Duke University 1963-1966, James B. Duke Professor Emeritus of Economics, Duke University
  - Interview footage: Paula D. McClain, Dean of the Graduate School, Duke University
    Historical note
    Professor McClain is a professor of Political Science and Public Policy. In 2012 she became the 14th Dean of the Duke University Graduate School and Vice Provost for Graduate Education, making her the first African American to serve as the dean of one of Duke's ten schools. She was also the first African American to serve as chair of the University's Academic Council.
  - Interview footage: Jean O'Barr, founding Director of Women's Studies
  - Interview footage: Ida Owens, 2013-2014
    Includes footage of Ida Owens interviewed at home and at the National Institute of Health (NIH) in Bethesda, MD, as well as the Duke University Bouchet Society Black Tie Dinner in 2013. Footage from the NIH includes an in interview with Nikhil Basu, staff scientist in Ida Owens' lab.
  - Interview Transcripts
  - Premiere event at Nasher Museum photos, video, and audio
  - Additional materials related to Ida Owens and documentary, 2013
    Includes Ivan Weiss's thesis proposal and PhD hooding ceremony.
  - Programs and promotional materials (Box 97)